<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="000style.xsl"?>
<teiCorpus>
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digitised and Encoded copy of Negro Slavery by Zachary MacAulay</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Transcribed from digital copy available from Recovered Histories at
                    http://www.recoveredhistories.org/pamphlet1.php?page=1&amp;orderby=MaxID&amp;catid=66</authority>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <biblFull>
                    <titleStmt>
                        <title>Negro Slavery; or, A View of Some of the More Prominent Features of
                            that State of Society, as it Exists in the United States of America and
                            in the Colonies of the West Indies, Especially in Jamaica</title>
                    </titleStmt>
                    <publicationStmt>
                        <publisher>Printed for Hatchard and Son, Piccadilly, and J. and A. Arch,
                            Cornhill</publisher>
                        <distributor>Sold Also by W. Graphel, Church street, and G. and J. Robison,
                            Castle Street, Liverpool.</distributor>
                        <date when="1823">1823</date>
                        <pubPlace>
                            <settlement>London</settlement>
                        </pubPlace>
                    </publicationStmt>
                </biblFull>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <TEI>
        <teiHeader>
            <fileDesc>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title/>
                </titleStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <authority>Transcribed by a student of Digital History at Sheffield Hallam
                        University</authority>
                </publicationStmt>
                <sourceDesc>
                    <bibl>
                        <biblScope>12</biblScope>
                    </bibl>
                </sourceDesc>
            </fileDesc>
        </teiHeader>
        <text>
            <body>
              <p> ...ease of the Black population has a better chance of being at least understood by them than us. Accordingly,
                  in some of the old states, and in all which have been recently admitted into the Union, slavery has been formally 
                  excluded from their constitution. The whole of the Eastern and a great part of the Central States, and many 
                  enlightened individuals even in the southern provinces, particularly the Quakers <interp key="Quakers involvement in the Abolition movement" n="E2BN and MLA East of London, Quakers/Society of Friends in The Abolition Project" cert="high" ref="http://abolition.e2bn.org/people_21.html"> </interp>, 
				  are declared enemies of 
                  the system of slavery. It is true, that, for the most part, they oppose it rather as a great political evil, 
				  than as a violation of the eternal obligations of humanity and justice : nevertheless, its extent is in this 
				  way gradually narrowing. With them there is no dispute, nor, indeed, can there be, respecting the opprobrious 
				  and humiliating facts of the case. With us, on the contrary, the only persons who, in general, have an 
				  opportunity of viewing with their own eyes the state of colonial bondage, are persons interested in upholding
				  it. And they are induced by tenderness for their own reputation, as well as by the strong feeling of interest,
				  and, we may add, by pride, to throw a veil over the enormities of the system, and to resist every attempt to
				  withdraw it. The advantage which America possesses in this important respect, would encourage a hope of 
				  eventual extinction of the evil at no very distant period, at least, at an earlier period than it would be 
				  reasonable to expect it in our own colonial possessions, but for another circumstance on which Mr. Hall <persName key="Hall, Francis" role="Lieutenant" ref="http://www.kouroo.info/kouroo/thumbnails/H/ColonelFrancisHall.pdf"> </persName>, 
				  incidentally, but feelingly, touches, and which must have a powerful influence in perpetuating the miseries
				  of slavery in the United States; we mean, the force of habit. Let any one consider, for a moment, the 
				  different sensations with which an individual who had never witnessed the infliction of a wound, and a 
				  practised surgeon, would regard the amputation of a limb;--or the disgust which would be excited in an...
				</p>
            </body>
        </text>
    </TEI>
</teiCorpus>